lbma.org.uk 2015-02-14

# LBMA - Legal Information

## This statement sets out how we use and protect any Personal Information that you give us when you use this website i.e. data which relates to an identifiable individual, such as names, addresses, email addresses and telephone numbers. If you have any questions about our policy or do not agree with it, please contact us prior to using this website.

By using this site you consent to the use of Personal Information as set out in this statement.

We may change this statement from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure you are happy with any changes. This statement is effective from 1st July 2007.

  * What information do we collect?
  * What do we do with the information we collect?
  * Who do we share this information with?
  * How to get copies of or amend the information we have colle
  * Security
  * Linking
  * Cookies

### What information do we collect?

In general, you can use this website without giving us any information. However we may collect personal and/or business details and information that you knowingly submit to us to be used for the purposes set out below.

### What do we do with the information we collect? 

We use this information to provide you with a better service, to respond to your enquiries, to control user access and internet site security, to keep you informed of any new products or services and to contact you for market research/customer survey purposes.

If you do not wish to receive any direct marketing material from us please contact us.

### Whom do we share this information with?

We will not transfer, disclose, sell, distribute or lease your Personal Information to any third parties not affiliated with LBMA, other than in the following circumstances: -

  * We have your permission or are required by law to do so.
  * We may disclose Personal Information to our agents and contractors in order to provide services to you.
  * We may provide Personal Information to credit reference agencies.
  * We may transfer Personal Information if we re-organise our business and/or sell part of our business.

These processes may include sending Personal Information to other countries, whose data protection laws may not be as extensive as in the European Economic Area. However, were appropriate, steps will be taken to ensure the same level of protection for the processing carried out in these countries as within the European Economic Area.

### How to get copies of or amend the information we have collected

You may request details of Personal Information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at The London Bullion Market Association, 1-2 Royal Exchange Buildings, Royal Exchange, London, EC3V 3LF.

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us as soon as possible and we will take appropriate steps to correct or update any information as soon as possible.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure and understand that privacy is important to you. We take reasonable precautions to ensure that the Personal Information we hold about you remains confidential. In order to prevent unauthorised access or modification, improper use or disclosure and unlawful destruction or accidental loss we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on line. This includes information security technology such as firewalls, anti-virus software and password access protection controls.

### Linking

We may link to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left our website, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Cookies/IP address 

We use cookies for certain areas of our website. Cookies are files that store information on your hard drive or browser that means that our website can recognise that you have visited our website before. They make it easier for you to maintain your preferences on the website, and by seeing how you use the website, we can tailor the website around your preferences and measure usability of the website. You can, should you choose, disable the cookies from your browser and delete all cookies currently stored on your computer. On Microsoft Internet Explorer, this can be done by selecting "Tools/Internet Options" and reviewing your privacy settings or selecting "delete cookies". This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. You can find out how to do this for your particular browser by clicking "help" on your browser's menu or by contacting us or by visiting <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html>. No information obtained from the cookie will be used by us for marketing purposes.

When you visit our site we may automatically log your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device. We will not use your IP address to identify you in any way. However, any activity we deem to be harmful to this website which can be attributed to a particular IP address may result in that IP address or range of IP addresses being disallowed further access to this website.
